therams.com 2017-11-19

# Los Angeles Rams | Privacy Policy

---  
  
**The Los Angeles Rams, LLC Website Privacy Policy**  

Revised January 1, 2016  

This privacy policy applies to the St. Louis Rams’ websites located at [www.therams.com](http://www.therams.com/) (the “Website”). The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.  

The Website is operated by Network Applications on behalf of The Los Angeles Rams, LLC (collectively, the "Los Angeles Rams", "we", "our", or "us"). Network Applications does not own any information submitted through this website and cannot use this information for its own purposes.  

The Los Angeles Rams, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html)  including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information while on the Website. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through mobile applications or mobile websites. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [info@rams.nfl.com](mailto:info@rams.nfl.com).  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint)  

When this privacy policy uses the term “personally identifiable information” or “personal information,” we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as your full name, street address or email address. When other information, such as a favorite team or player, is associated with personal information, it also becomes personally identifiable information for the purposes of this privacy policy.  

Please note that the Services are directed towards users who reside in the United States. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, storage, processing, and transfer of your information in and to the United States, or other countries and territories, pursuant to the laws of the United States. While some of these countries may not offer the same level of privacy protection as your own, we commit to uphold the privacy protections as explained in this Policy.

Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.  

  1. Types Of Information That May Be Collected

  2. How Information May Be Collected

  3. How We Use The Information Collected

  4. With Whom The Information May Be Shared

  5. Security

  6. Links To Other Websites

  7. A Special Note For Parents Concerning Privacy

  8. Notification Of Changes And Your Acceptance Of The Privacy Policy

  9. Correcting/Updating Personal Information

  10. Your California Privacy Rights

  11. Questions About This Privacy Policy

Types of information that may be collected  

The following are the types of information we may collect:  

**Information You Provide Us:** In the course of using the website, we may ask you to provide us with certain information, including contact information, such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, fax number. birth date, gender, favorite Rams player, unique identifiers, such as your user name, password, demographic information, such as your date of birth, age, gender, education, household income, occupation, ticket holder status, game attendance, home ownership, marital status, or number of children, financial information, such as your credit card number, or similar information.  

**Tell-A-Friend:** If you choose to use our referral service, called “Email This To A Friend” to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Stlouisrams.com does not store this information. It is for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.  

**Chat Rooms/Blogs/Forums**   
 If you use a bulletin board, chat room, blog or forum on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.  

**Site Usage Information:** We may receive and store certain types of internet usage information whenever you visit the Website, such as your browser type, click-stream data (pages, stories, ect.), and IP Address. For more details about how this information is used, please refer to “IP Address & Click-Stream Data” below.  

**Email Communications:** When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation noting you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have opted to receive or not to receive.  

**Information from Other Sources:** We may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the personal information we have collected. Examples include offline promotions and sweepstakes operated by the Los Angeles Rams, the NFL and our sponsors. Online promotions and sweepstakes operated by the Rams or our sponsors, such as the Coin Toss Captain, MBNA credit card application and other Rams determined promotional activities. This information is used to fulfill the promotion or sweepstakes and contact the winner. Also, while participating in any of these promotions or sweepstakes, the user may choose to participate in other Rams offerings like the email newsletter or to receive a Rams merchandise catalog. In these instances we will use your information to send you the email or the catalog.  

How information may be collected  

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:  

**Registration:** You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.  

Single Sign On Services: You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect, Twitter, or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.  Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.  

**Newsletters and Website Emails:** We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email. You may contact the Rams Digital team to unsubscribe: [info@rams.nfl.com](mailto:info@rams.nfl.com)  

**Contests or Sweepstakes:** We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes, (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used). We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner’s page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website, and collect your information. In those cases, where we are not the operator or host of the contest or sweepstakes, we do not collect your information and we have no control over the information collected from you. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.  

Our website offers promotions that involve other parties, to varying degrees. Here is how we treat user information in each type of promotion:  

  1. Promotions run by the Rams and we do not share information with 3rd party sponsor: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. In these promotions, the Rams privacy policy applies. The Rams do not share this information with any 3rd parties.

  2. Promotions run by the Rams, but collected information may be used by the Rams and/or 3rd party sponsor: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. Users will be given the option to allow the 3rd party sponsor to see their information. This option will be signified by checking a checkbox that reads “Receive email from the St. Louis Rams regarding special offers from the Rams and our partners.” In these cases, the 3rd party sponsor may see the information. Once the information is transferred to the 3rd party, the 3rd party’s privacy policy applies.3. Promotions where the 3rd party collects the information: In these cases, the Rams do not collect the information. The page upon which the registration occurs will clearly look like the 3rd party’s website, and not the Rams. The 3rd party’s privacy policy will apply to collected information. In some cases, the 3rd party may provide some information back to the Rams. This will only occur if the user chooses to allow the Rams to see the information. When the information is transferred to the Rams, the Rams privacy policy will apply. Surveys or Voting: From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.

**Games:** When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.  

**Cookies:** As with many Websites, our Website uses a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify you, just the computer that is used to visit the site. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know non-personally identifiable information, like what web browser is being used to access the website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. Cookies are associated with your personal information in our internal logs.  

**IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data:** We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.  

**Third Party Tracking:** The use of cookies by our tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy policy.  We do not have access or control over these cookies.  Tracking utility companies use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.  

Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personally identifiable information.  

**Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting:** We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out.  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads.  

**Transaction Information:** If you conduct a financial transaction with our Website, such as purchasing merchandise in our pro shop, purchasing tickets to promotional and community events, purchasing tickets through the Rams/Ticketmaster system or subscribing to services offered on our Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the information, products or other services that you order, and to invoice you. For your protection, such information is collected and stored through encrypted means.  

How we use the information collected  

As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:  

\- contact you about the Website;  
\- contact you relating to your membership status;  
\- confirm or fulfill an order you have made;  
\- inform you of a prize you have won;  
\- monitor or improve the use of the Website;  
\- customize the advertising and content you see;  
\- monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Website; and  
\- send you promotional material or special offers on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.  
With whom the information may be shared  

At times, we may share your personal information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others and the ways in which you may opt-out of having your information shared:  

**Agents:** We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They may have access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.  

Here are the current examples of this:  

Season Ticket Account Manager:  
[https://oss.ticketmaster.com/html/home.htmI?team=rams&l=EN&STAGE=1](https://oss.ticketmaster.com/html/home.htmI?team=rams&l=EN&STAGE=1)  

This page is accessed by clicking on “Season Ticket Acct Mgr” under Tickets. This is operated by Ticketmaster, who handles some season ticket management and payment processes for the Rams. This page is operated by Ticketmaster, but has the appearance of the Rams website. When users submit information to this page, it is used by Ticketmaster to fulfill ticketing services for the Rams and ticket buyers. The information user’s submit on this page is subject to  

Ticketmaster’s privacy policy.  
<http://www.ticketmaster.com/h/privacy.html?tm_link=tm_home_i_pp>  

Rams Online Pro Shop:   
<http://www.ramsfanshop.com/>  

This page is accessed by clicking on “Pro Shop catalog” in the main navigation, or other places throughout the Rams website. This page is operated by the Rams. The order fulfillment, customer service and credit card transactions are handled by AMP Sports, through an agreement with the Rams. When users submit information to this page, it is used by AMP Sports to fulfill merchandise services and perform customer service. The information user’s submit on this page is subject to the Rams’ privacy policy.  

**Aggregate Information:** We may share aggregate information, such as demographics and Website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations. When this type of information is shared, the other parties do not have access to your personally identifiable information.  

**Opt-In / Opt-Out Offers:** When you provide us with personal information, you may be presented with the opportunity to share your personal information with third parties for various purposes, such as receiving information or special offers. An opt-in/opt-out message will ask you if you would like your information to be shared. When you allow us to share your personal information with third parties, we require third parties who have access to that information to agree to abide by our current Website privacy policy. Once the information is transferred, however, we cannot control the privacy practices of these other companies.  

**Third-Party Offers:** Throughout the Website you may be presented with opportunities to receive special offers from third parties. By participating in these offers, you consent to allowing your information to be shared with third parties. When you allow us to share your personal information with third parties, we require third parties who have access to that information to agree to abide by our current Website privacy policy. We cannot control the privacy practices of these other companies, however, and you should review the privacy practices of such companies prior to providing your personally identifiable information.  

Users have the ability to choose for third parties to see portions of user’s personal information. On the Website, here are the types of promotions and the ways in which a 3rd party may use user’s information:

1\. Promotions run by the Rams and we do not share information with 3rd party sponsor: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. In these promotions, the Rams privacy policy applies. The Rams do not share this information with any 3rd parties.

2.Promotions run by the Rams, but collected information may be used by the Rams and/or 3rd party sponsor: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. Users will be given the option to allow the 3rd party sponsor to see their information. This option will be signified by checking a checkbox that reads “Receive email from the St. Louis Rams regarding special offers from the Rams and our partners.” In these cases, the 3rd party sponsor may see the information. Once the information is transferred to the 3rd party, the 3rd party’s privacy policy applies.

3\. Promotions where the 3rd party collects the information: In these cases, the Rams do not collect the information. The page upon which the registration occurs will clearly look like the 3rd party’s website, and not the Rams. The 3rd party’s privacy policy will apply to collected information. In some cases, the 3rd party may provide some information back to the Rams. This will only occur if the user chooses to allow the Rams to see the information. When the information is transferred to the Rams, the Rams privacy policy will apply.  

**Other Promotional Offers:** We may send offers to you on behalf of our marketing partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may:  

  1. Edit your profile online: edit profile <http://rams.ed4.net/profile/signup.cfm>

  2. Use an opt out message in a Rams email newsletter

Third-Party Ad Serving & Audience and Traffic Measurement Services: In the future, the Website may use a third party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Website or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Website. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Website and other Websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or Websites you might be interested in. Audience and Traffic Measurement Services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from our Website by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Website cookies, the Website's advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies. Currently, the Rams do not employ 3rd parties to handle these services.  

**Business Transfers:** In the event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personally identifiable information is one of the business assets transferred, all personally identifiable information that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer. See “YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTIFICATION OF CHANGES TO THE POLICY” section below.  

**Administrative or Legal Process:** Your personal information may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, law enforcement agencies, to protect our rights, or protect the rights of other users of this website.  

Links to other Websites  

You should be aware that when you are on the Website you could be directed to other Websites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different Website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Website's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other Websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a Website that is linked to our Website, you should consult that Website's privacy policy before providing any personal information.  

The Website utilizes framing techniques to make it appear that the user is still on the site when the user is actually on a third party Web site. For example when you use our Chat feature you will be taken to a third party site, but the page is framed with the Los Angeles Rams branding. Note that the third party’s privacy policy governs the collection and use of the data collected on these pages.  

Security  

This Website incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Your personally identifiable information is transferred to our computers utilizing encryption software. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required.  

A special note for parents concerning privacy  

The Website is a general audience Website. However, we do collect information about children under 13 from parents so they may sign their child up for our Kids club.  The information we collect is your child’s name, date of birth and the address provided by a parent, guardian or purchaser of the Rams Kids Club membership. We use this information to allow you to sign your child up for the kids club and for you to receive Rams merchandise as a part of the Kids Club membership, for your child.    If you no longer wish to allow your child to be part of the Kids club or wish to delete all information collected about your child, please contact us at [privacy@URL.com](mailto:privacy@URL.com).

We will not share your child’s personal information with any third party for any reason.  If you feel we have collected personal information from your child directly, please contact us at the email address listed above to request immediate deletion of that information.  We do not set any tracking technologies within the Kids section of the site that may be behavioral in nature.  

The Internet offers children wonderful educational and entertainment resources. Your guidance and involvement are essential to help ensure that children have a safe and rewarding online experience. We encourage you to visit the Direct Marketing Association's Web Website [(www.the-dma.org)](http://www.the-dma.org/index.php) and explore the Get CyberSavvy! Program as well as the GetNetWise Website [(www.getnetwise.org)](http://www.getnetwise.org/) to learn more about parental control tools.  

Our acceptance of the privacy policy and notification of changes to the policy  

By using this Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on our website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the new privacy policy, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address.  

Correcting/Updating personal information  

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your email address or zip code), or if you no longer desire to access our Website, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by the following methods:  

  1. Edit your profile online: edit profile [(http://www.stlouisrams.com/reg/login/)](http://www.stlouisrams.com/community/register/login.html)

  2. Use an opt out message in a Rams email newsletter

  3. Email us at [info@rams.nfl.com](mailto:info@rams.nfl.com)

  4. Write us at: Website Opt Out, Los Angeles Rams, 29899 Agoura Road, Agoura Hills, CA 91301

Please allow us ten (10) days to complete your opt out request.  In addition, we will respond to all access requests including requests for deletion within thirty (30) days.  

Data Retention  

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at questions@rams.nfl.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.   

Your California privacy rights  

A California privacy law that went into effect on January 1, 2005, allows California residents to obtain specific information about a business’s privacy practices if it shares information with other companies for those companies’ direct marketing purposes.  

As explained in this privacy policy, whenever you agree to let us collect personal information about you, we will always provide you with an option to prevent this information from being shared for non-administrative purposes with third parties. You can exercise this option at any time by following the steps outlined above.  

Because this website has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may opt-in / opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes, we are not required to provide you with this information. If you are a California resident and have questions about our compliance with this law, please send an email to [info@rams.nfl.com](mailto:info@rams.nfl.com) or write to us at:  

CA Privacy Rights  
Los Angeles Rams  
29899 Agoura Road  
Agoura Hills, CA 91301  

Questions about this privacy policy  

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the privacy practices of this Website, contact [info@rams.nfl.com](mailto:info@rams.nfl.com).  

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to:  

Digital Media Manager  
Los Angeles Rams  
29899 Agoura Road, Agoura Hills, CA 91301  
(314) 982-7267
